David Goodger

819-700-2816 · goodger@python.org · david.goodger.org · linkedin.com/in/goodger/ · Ottawa & Montreal, Canada

Software Engineer/Architect · Systems Engineer/Analyst · Project Manager · Trainer

Software/Systems Engineer with professional experience in the medical device industry, the financial sector, and automation/manufacturing. Experience in project management and training. Recognized expert in the Python programming language. Extensive experience with markup languages for documentation, document processing, and data interchange. Cross-platform systems development experience, ranging from GUI desktop applications to web services to command-line tools.

Strengths include: effective communication between technical and non-technical/business audiences, public speaking, excellent writing and editing skills, thorough and tenacious problem solving. International experience, with written and spoken Japanese and French.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Python (expert), Perl, Lisp, Visual Basic, C, C++, SQL, Bash.

Development Methodologies: Agile (Scrum, Extreme Programming), design patterns, refactoring, TDD/test-driven development, UML.

Operating Systems: Linux/UNIX/QNX/Solaris, Windows, Mac OS X.

Documentation Technologies: XML, XSL, SGML; HTML/XHTML, CSS; Docutils/reStructuredText; Unicode; document analysis, DTD design; document data processing.

Experience

Medtronic Inc. (formerly Corventis), Mounds View, Minnesota, USA **Principal Systems Engineer.**

January 2013 - May 2020

- Projects: SEEQ mobile cardiac telemetry patch & CareLink cardiac patient monitoring service.
- Systems & data analysis.
- Software systems requirements development.
- Agile Scrum Product Owner.

Programmer/Analyst. Developed desktop GUI software for an electronic medical device system (SEEQ mobile cardiac telemetry patch). Technologies: Python, wxPython GUI toolkit, USB communication, web services, Dropbox integration.

Independent Consultant, Montréal, Québec, Canada **Programmer/Analyst, Trainer, Systems Administrator.**

December 2008 - January 2013

CDP Capital Inc., Montréal, Québec, Canada

July 2005 – June 2012

Programmer/Analyst. Developed software tools for investment data analysis, including foreign exchange order management system and index fund management software. Technologies: Python, wxPython & tkInter GUI toolkits. (Full-time employee July 2005 – December 2008; consultant December 2008 – June 2012)

Python Software Foundation, remote & Chicago, Illinois, USA December 2008 – September 2009 **Conference Coordinator.** Chaired the PyCon 2009 & 2008 Python community conferences, working (mostly remotely) with volunteer organizers and professional meeting planners. Chaired PyCon 2008 as a volunteer. **Member of the Board of Directors** (elected volunteer, February 2006 – July 2009)

Open-Source Projects

Docutils: Documentation Utilities (http://docutils.sourceforge.net) — project coordinator and architect

Polyform Puzzler (http://puzzler.sourceforge.net/) — project coordinator and architect

Python (the programming language, http://www.python.org) — contributing developer; author or co-author of several Python Enhancement Proposals (http://www.python.org)

Additional Relevant Experience

ELM Machine Service Inc., Cambridge, Ontario, Canada

Consulting Developer. Developed a control panel and data acquisition application for a PLC-based industrial gauge system, using open-source rapid application development tools (Python, wxPython, Boa Constructor).

ATS Automation Tooling Systems Inc., Cambridge, Ontario, Canada

Systems Administrator & Software Developer. In charge of network and server systems in a mixed (Windows & QNX) environment, office and production facility with over 100 workstations. Developed engineering data processing applications & system maintenance solutions.

Rikai Ltd., Tokyo, Japan

President and Founder. Software development & information technology consulting.

Uniscope, Inc., Tokyo, Japan

Operations Manager & Technical Team Leader; Developer. Project & personnel management; research & development; analysis, design, and development of document processing, workflow, relational and object database, intranet, and internet systems; systems administration (Unix/Solaris, Windows platforms).

Embassy of Canada, Tokyo, Japan

Network Systems Administrator & User Support Manager. Systems administration, user support, training, programming, & troubleshooting (150 Windows clients, Unix servers).

Gunma Prefectural Board of Education (Japan Exchange & Teaching Program), Gunma, Japan Assistant English Teacher

Education & Certificates

Bachelor of Science, Major in Computer Science

McGill University, Montréal, Québec, Canada

Certified Scrum Product Owner

Scrum Alliance, Minneapolis, MN

Japanese-Language Proficiency Test, Level 2

Japan Foundation & Japan Educational Exchanges and Services, Tokyo, Japan

Publications

Hello World! Computer Programming for Kids and Other Beginners (Manning, 2009) — Technical Editor

Python For Dummies (Wiley, 2006) — Technical Editor

Python Cookbook, Second Edition (O'Reilly & Associates, 2005) — contributor (section 1.23)

Python Cookbook (O'Reilly & Associates, 2002) — contributor (sections 15.4 & 2.3)

Professional Linux Programming (Wrox Press, 2000) — author of Chapter 15, "Python," a programmer's introduction to the Python programming language

Keynote Presentations & Tutorials

Python in India — Keynote presentation (PyCon India, Bangalore, India, 2010)

wxPython I: Introduction to GUI Programming & wxPython II: GUI Programming and MVC — Tutorials (PyCon 2010, Atlanta GA; PyCon 2008, Chicago IL)

How to Become an Invited Speaker — Keynote presentation (RuPy 2009, Poznan, Poland)

Code Like a Pythonista: Idiomatic Python — Tutorial (PyCon 2007, Dallas, Texas; OSCON 2007, Portland, Oregon)

Text and Data Processing — Tutorial (PyCon 2006, Dallas Texas)